<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?>

<cheatsheet title="Working with the ISO 27001 model in verinice.">

  <intro>
    <description>
      In this tutorial you will learn the basic operations when dealing with the ISO 27001 perspective
      in verinice.
    </description>
  </intro>
  
  <item title="Creating Assets">
    <description>
      In the view "Information Security Model" you can create objects and object groups. The predefined
      categories for objects are displayed when you create a new root object (organization object).
      Click the button <b>Add new organization</b> which is located at the top right edge of the view.
      An organization object means a scope, a department or even the entire organization.
      <br /><br />
      Now create an asset group. To do this, click the right mouse button on the category "Assets".
      You will see a context menu from which you should choose to option <b>Add New Asset Group ...</b>.
      Now you have created a group object for assets. A group object corresponds to a folder in the
      operating system. This object can contain other asset objects or other asset group objects.
      This way you can build completely custom hierarchical object groups and objects.
      <br /><br />
      Rename the asset group just created by entering the title text "Client PCs" in the editor.
      Save by pressing the key combination <b>Ctrl+S</b>.
      <br /><br />
      Now create an asset for the group "Client PCs" by right-clicking and selecting <b>Add New Asset
      ...</b>.
      <br /><br />
      Now an asset object is created and attached to the group object you created. The editor for
      entering the data for the new asset appears automatically on the right site. Enter some
      fictitious data here and save it with the key combination <b>Ctrl+S</b> or by closing the view.
      On closing of unsaved view content you will be automatically asked if you want to save it.
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="Modelling Controls">
  	<description>
  		When working with catalogs such as ISO/IEC 27001 in
		verinice, you have to import or create the corresponding controls first.
		
		The easiest way to do that is to use the verinice risk catalog which is
		available in the verinice.SHOP:
		<b>http://shop.verinice.com</b> <br />
		
		Alternatively it is possible to import the required controls from a
		CSV-file or to simply create them
		in verinice manually.
		
		The CSV-import is described in the verinice-manual,
		which is available in the verinice.SHOP as well.<br/>
		You can also get free information on our websites, in the verinice-forum
		and from our Youtube channel.
		<br/>
		In this tutorial we assume that you are using the verinice risk catalog.
		<br /><br />
		
		By double-clicking on a control you can now edit the
		information for this control in
		the editor view: open the control "8.1.1 Inventory of assets".
		
		Set the field "Implemented" to "yes" by selecting the correct entry in the
		drop-down menu.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Creating Relations">
    <description>
      In verinice diverse relations between the objects are possible. To create a simple relation,
      just connect the newly created asset object with the newly inserted control via drag and drop.
      You can see that in the relation view the relation is just created. A matching relation type is
      also visible. Double-click on the referenced object in the relation view. The referenced object
      will be opened in the editor view.
      <br /><br />
      Explore what types of relations are possible. If there are types of relations missing, these can
      easily be added or modified. How to do this is described at <b>http://www.verinice.com/en</b>. If you have
      any questions, please use our forum: <b>http://www.forum.verinice.com</b>.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Inserting Documents">
    <description>
      Imagine, you have just signed a customer non-disclosure agreement (NDA). In it, you commit to a
      high penalty when data should be revealed. Additionally all customer data has to be encrypted.
      <br /><br />
      First we load the document into verinice. Right-click the group "Documents" in the view
      "Information Security Model" (ISM). Now select <b>Add Document ...</b>.
      <br /><br />
      Please enter "NDA Customer1" as title in the editor view. Change the "Document Type" to
      "Contract". Open the files view from the view menu. Select the document object in the ISM view
      again if it is not already selected. Then drag any PDF document as a placeholder for our NDA into
      the files view.
      <br /><br />
      You can now enter meta information for the attached file -- for example the version of the document.
      When you press <b>Ctrl+S</b>, the document will be uploaded and linked with the object in the ISM
      view. You can open the attached file by clicking the <b>Show</b> button. If you use the
      verinice.PRO server, the document is immediately available to everyone in your organization
      who has access to it.
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="Modelling Requirements">
    <description>
      The NDA demanded the encryption of customer data. So right-click on the group "Requirements",
      then on <b>Add Requirement ...</b>. Change the name to "Encryption" in the editor.
      Now create a relation by dragging and dropping the requirement object onto the document
      object. The link appears in the relations view.
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="Comply Requirements With Controls">
    <description>
      Right-click the "Controls" group in the ISM tree, select <b>Add Control...</b>.
      Change the name to "Customer data must be encrypted" in the editor view. Save by pressing
      <b>Ctrl+S</b>. Link by dragging and dropping the control with the requirement "Encryption".
      The relations view indicates that this requirement is now met by the control.
    </description>
  </item>
  
  <item title="Creating More Relations">
    <description>
      In the same manner as described you can create more relations. For example, you can document
      which person is responsible for implementing the measures. You should also create the customer
      data as an asset object and document the accompanying owner person.
      <br /><br />
      The relation types are generated automatically. If a type is incorrect, you can change it in the
      relations view. Simply click the type of relationship. If there
      are alternatives they will be listed now.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Thank You!">
    <description>
      That's it! This was a small overview of the functions of verinice to help you comply with the
      ISO 27001 standard. More information is available on our website <b>http://www.verinice.com/en</b>.
    </description>
  </item>
  
</cheatsheet>
