<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?> 
<cheatsheet title="Working with the ISO 27001 model in verinice.">
	<intro>
		<description>
			In this tutorial you will learn the basic operations
   when dealing with the ISO 27001 perspective in verinice.
			<br/>
		</description>
	</intro>
	<item title="Creating Assets">
		<description>
		In the view "Information Security Model" you can create objects and object groups.
  The predefined categories for objects are displayed when you create a new root object 
  (organization object). Click on 
  "Add new organization" button which is located at the top right
  edge of the view. An organization object means a scope,
  a department or even the entire organization.
		<br/>
		<br/>
		Now create an asset group. To do this, click the right mouse button on the
  category "Assets". You will see a context menu from which you should choose to option 
  "Add New Asset Group ... ". Now you have created a group object for assets. 
  A group object corresponds to a folder of an operating system. 
  This object can contain other asset objects or other asset group objects. You can build 
  completely custom hierarchical object groups and objects so.  
		<br/>
  Rename the newly created asset group by entering the title text "Client PC" appeared in the 
  left window (editor view). Save by pressing the key combination Ctrl+S.	
		<br/>
		<br/>
  Now create for the group "Client PC" an asset object by right-clicking and selecting "Add New Asset ...".		
		<br/>
	 Now an asset object is created and attached to the group object you created. The editor view 
	 for entering the data for the new asset appears automatically on the right site. Enter here some 
	 fictitious data and save it with the key combination Ctrl+S or by closing the view. On closing 
	 of unsaved view content you will be automatically asked if you want to save this.	
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Modelling Controls">
		<description>
		Before starting the procedure, you must import the catalog first.
  The catalog "ISO 27001 Implementation Guidance" can be found on http://v.de 
		under "Downloads".
		<br/><br/> 
		To insert controls into the "Information Security Model", you need 
		drag'n'drop the required controls from the catalog view 
		onto the group "Controls" in the view "Information Security Model". 
		Do this with the control "11.5 Responsibility for assets".
  <br/><br/> 
  By double-clicking the inserted controls, you can now edit the information 
  for this control in the editor view. Choose "Yes" for the item "Implemented". 
		</description>
	</item>
	
	<item title="Creating Relations">
		<description>
  In verinice diverse relations between the objects are possible. 
  To create a simple relation, just connect the newly created asset 
  object with the newly inserted control via drag'n'drop. You can see that 
  in the relation view the relation is just created. A matching relation 
  type is also visible. Double-click on the referenced object in the relation view. 
  The referenced object will be opened in the editor view.  
  <br/> 
		<br/>
  Explore what 
  types of relations are possible. If there are types of relations missing, these can 
  easily be added or existing ones be modified. How to realize this is described on 
  http://v.de. If you have any questions, please use our forum: http://www.forum.verinice.org 
		</description>
	</item>
 <item
       title="Inserting Documents">
    <description>
       Imagine, you have just signed a customer non-disclosure agreement (NDA). 
       In it, you commit to a high penalty when data should be revealed. Additionally all customer 
       data hast to be encrypted.   
       <br/><br/>
       First we load the document into verinice. Right-click in the 
       view "Information Security Model" (ISM) on the group "Documents". 
       Now select "Add Document ...".
       <br/><br/>
          Please enter "NDA Customer1" as title in the editor view. Change the "Document Type" 
          to "Contract". Open the files view from the view menu. Select the document object in the ISM view 
          again if it is not already selected. Then drag any PDF 
          document as a placeholder for our NDA in the files view. 
 <br/><br/>
          You can now enter meta information for the attached file - for example the version of the document. 
          When you press Ctrl+S, the document will be uploaded and is linked now with 
          the object in the ISM view. You can open the attached file by clicking on 
          the "Show" button. If you use the verinice.PRO server, the document is 
          immediately available to everyone in your organization who has access to it. 
    </description>
 </item>
 <item
       title="Modelling Requirements">
    <description>
      The NDA demanded the encryption of customer data. So right-click on 
      the group "Requirements", then on "Add Requirement ...". Change the name to 
      "Encryption" in the editor view. 
      Now create a relation by dragging and dropping the requirement object onto the document 
      object. The link appears now in the relations view. 
    </description>
 </item>
 <item
 					title="Comply Requirements With Controls">
    <description>
       Right-click on the "Controls" group in the ISM tree, select "Add Control..." now.  
       Change 
       the name to "Customer data must be encrypted" in the editor view. Save by pressing Ctrl+S. 
       Link by dragging and dropping the control with the requirement "Encryption". 
       The relations view indicates that this requirement is now met by the control. 
    </description>
 </item>
 <item
       title="Creating More Relations">
    <description>
       In the same manner as described, you can create more relations now.  For 
       example, you can document which person is responsible for implementing 
       the measures. You should 
       also create the customer data as an asset object and document the accompanying owner person. 
       The relation types are generated automatically. It one type is incorrect, you can change the 
       type in the relations view. Simply click on the type of relationship. If there 
       are alternatives - they will be listed now. 
    </description>
 </item>
	
 <item
       title="Thank You!">
    <description>
       That's it! This was a small overview of the functions of verinice to fulfill the 
       ISO 27001 standard. More information is available on our website: http://v.de 
    </description>
 </item>
</cheatsheet>
