<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?> 
<cheatsheet title="Getting started">

	<intro 
		>
		<description>
			<b>Welcome to verinice!</b>
			<br/>
			<br/>
			This tutorial will help you to configure verinice and guide you along the first few steps.
		</description>
	</intro>
	
	<item title="Switch to ISM perspective">
	<description>
	Since you're reading this in English, we assume that you wish to use the ISM perspective. 
	This perspective allows you to model requirements and controls, to calculate risk and generate reports. 
		<br/>
		<br/>
		Open the ISM perspective now by clicking on the menu "View > Show Perspective ... > ISM Perspective".
	</description>
	</item>

	<item
		title="Download control catalog">

		<description>
			First you need to download a control catalog. Some free catalogs are available from the verinice website.
			You can also create your own catalogs using Excel or OpenOffice and import them into verinice.
			<br/>
			<br/>
			Use your webbrowser and open the following URL: 
			<br/>
			<b>http://www.verinice.org/en/download/</b>
			<br/>
			<br/>
			Download the catalog &quot;Implementation Guidance for ISO 27001&quot; from the Section &quot;CATALOGS AND MORE&quot;.
			<br/>
			<br/>
			Save the file on your hard drive.
		</description>
	</item>
	
	<item title="Import control catalog">
	<description>
		Now you have to import the catalog file. On the left-hand side of the verinice workbench you will find the &quot;Catalogs&quot; view.
		Click on the leftmost button (&quot;Import catalog...&quot;).
		<br/>
		<br/>
		Choose your downloaded catalog file and click &quot;OK&quot;.
	</description>
	</item>

	<item title="Create a scope">
	<description>
	The catalog is now being loaded. When the parser has finished, you will see the contents in the catalog view.
	<br/><br/>
	Open the browser view (&quot;View > Show view ... > Object Browser&quot;). Click on a control to show its contents in the browser view.
	<br/><br/>
	To actually work with the imported controls, you have to create your organization in the database. Go to the view &quot;Information Security Model&quot;.
	It should be displayed in the middle of the verinice workbench. Click on the rightmost button (&quot;Add new organization&quot;). 
	Drag some controls from the catalog view to the &quot;Controls&quot; group underneath your new organization. The controls will be created. 
	Double-click on them to open the editor for each control.
	</description>
	<onCompletion>
	Excellent! If you want to continue, you'll find more tutorials in the Help menu.
	</onCompletion>
	
	</item>
		
	
</cheatsheet>
