<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?>
<cheatsheet title="Getting started">

  <intro>
    <description>
      <b>Welcome to verinice!</b>
      <br /><br />
      This tutorial will help you to configure verinice and guide you along the first few steps.
    </description>
  </intro>

  <item title="Switch to ISM perspective">
    <description>
      Since you're reading this in English, we assume that you wish to use the ISM perspective.
      This perspective allows you to model requirements and controls, to calculate risk and generate reports.
      <br /><br />
      Open the ISM perspective by clicking the menu item <b>View > Show Perspective... >
      ISM Perspective</b>.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Import control catalog">
    <description>
      First you need to import a control catalog. You have to import the catalog file. On the left-hand side of the verinice workbench you will find
      the "Catalogs" view. Click the leftmost button ("Import catalog...").
      <br /><br />
      Choose your downloaded or manually created (e.g. using Excel or OpenOffice) catalog file and click <b>OK</b>.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Create a scope">
    <description>
      The catalog is now being loaded. After the parser has finished, you will see the contents in the
      catalog view.
      <br /><br />
      Open the browser view (<b>View > Show View > Object Browser</b>). Click a control to show
      its contents in the browser view.
      <br /><br />
      To actually work with the imported controls, you have to create your organization in the database.
      Go to the view "Information Security Model". It should be displayed in the middle of the verinice
      workbench. Click the rightmost button ("Add new organization"").
      <br /><br />
      Drag some controls from the catalog view to the "Controls" group underneath your new organization.
      The controls will be created. Double-click them to open the editor for each control.
    </description>
    <onCompletion>
      Excellent! If you want to continue, you'll find more tutorials in the Help menu.
    </onCompletion>

  </item>

</cheatsheet>
