<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<cheatsheet title="Information Security Management with verinice und Greenbone">

  <intro>
    <description>
      In connection with a <b>Greenbone</b>-vulnerabilityscanner (<b>www.greenbone.net</b>) as well as an
      OpenVAS vulnerability scanner (<b>www.openvas.org</b>) verinice enables an effective vulnerability
      management.<br />
      <br />
      In the ISM-perspective verinice supports you in performing the risk analysis and the vulnerability management
      after importing the results of a vulnerability scan. Exclusive in verinice.PRO there is an additional task
      workflow for the elimination of vulnerabilities implemented.
    </description>
  </intro>

  <item title="ISM Vulnerability Scan in Greenbone">
    <description>
      With the Greenbone Security Manager you can automatically perform vulnerabilityscans of your systems.<br />
      <br />
      Please refer to the Greenbone user manual or visit the Greenbone website <b>www.greenbone.net</b> for a
      detailled description how to perform an ISM-vulnerabilityscan. You will find a special scan configuration and
      an verinice-ISM report plugin to use in verinice for download.
    </description>
  </item>

<item title="Create Notes for Scan Results">
    <description>
      To make sure that those vulnerabilities found in a Greenbone scan will be created as objects in verinice you
      need to create notes for them in Greenbone. These procedure enables fine tuning of your vulnerability import in
      verinice.<br />
      <br />
      In case a vulnerability has no note assigned the scanned system will be created as an asset in verinice without
      the corresponding vulnerability!<br />
      <br />
      To create notes in Greenbone click on the button <b>Actions > Add Note</b> in the list of found vulnerabilities.<br />
      <br />
      You should create only as many notes as your administrators can realistically work on in a given 
      time frame. You should see the list of all vulnerabilities as your backlog, from which you select 
      the most important ones for immediate remediation.<br />
      <br />
      You do this by adding notes to them. In the first line of each description you can add keywords 
      which are used by verinice to group them. Usually it is advisable to group the notes by affected
      application. For instance you can set up one group for all notes regarding your PDF-Reader. To do 
      that, enter the following in the first line: <b>+PdfReader</b>.<br />
      In the second line and following you can add your task description for this particular note which 
      can be as long as you want.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Exporting the Scan Results">
    <description>
      Select the report of a successful scan in the Greenbone menu <b>Scan management > reports</b>.<br />
      <br />
      Export the results of the ISM-vulnerability scan as vna-file by selecting <b>verinice ISM</b> as the format in
      the corresponding drop-down-box and start the export by clicking on the button <b>Download filtered report</b>.
      Greenbone will save the vna-file in the download directory in your system environment.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Importing ISM Vulnerability Scan">
    <description>
      Switch to the ISM Perspective in verinice using menu <b>View > Show perspective > ISM Perspective</b>. Start
      the import by clicking the button <b>Import organisation from file...</b>. Select the previously exported
      Greenbonen ISM-Report by clicking the button <b>Select file...</b>, keep the default values for all other
      parameters in the dialogue.<br />
      <br />
      The results of the vulnerability scan can be found in the group <b>Imported objects</b> in the following object
      groups:<br />
      <br />
      Assets GSM-Scan = all scanned systems<br />
      Vulnerabilities GSM-Scan = all found Vulnerabilities<br />
      Controls GSM-Scan = controls for the correction of found vulnerabilities<br />
      Scenarios GSM-Scan = newly created scenarios for allocation of assets and vulnerabilities<br />
      <br />
      With double mouseclick on any imported asset in the chapter <b>Greenbone GSM</b> of the editor view the details
      for the vulnerability are shown. Plase notice, that the checkbox for the chapter <b>Greenbone_GSM</b> must be set
      in the menu <b>Edit > Preferences > Editor settings</b>.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Risk Analysis">
    <description>
      You can transfer the imported assets, controls, scenarios and vulnerabilities one by one into your existing
      organisation or moove the complete organisation to the top level by navigating to <b>imported objects</b> and
      chooese the option <b>Cut</b> from the context menu (right mouseclick).<br />
      <br />
      Close the group <b>imported objects</b> to make sure that no further selection is active and insert the
      organisation with right mouseclick and the option <b>Insert</b> to insert the organisation on the top level.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Grouping Objcts">
    <description>
      For a clear view and to create tasks the imported assets and controls can be grouped according to the <b>GSM
      tags</b>. To do so select the group <b>Assets GSM-Scan</b> or <b>Controls GSM-Scan</b> and choose the right click
      option <b>Group by tags...</b>.<br />
      <br />
      Additionally each asset group can be assigned a responsible person. Assumed you allready created persons in your
      organisation you can create the relation simply using drag and drop with one or more asset groups.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Workflow - Rectifying Vulnerabilites (verinice.PRO only)">
    <description>
      verinice provides a specific workflow to elliminate the vulnerabilities ad support you effectively in this
      process.<br />
      <br />
      To create the tasks for ellimination of the vulnerabilities select any organisation and choose the right click
      option <b>Task > Greenbone: Start vulnerability process...</b>.<br />
      <br />
      The created tasks of the type <b>Recitify vulnerability</b> include  controls, scenarios und assets that are
      linked to a control group. Any responsible person can now work on these tasks in the task view, available from
      the menu <b>View > Show View > Tasks</b> or in the section <b>tasks</b> in the webfrontend.<br />
      <br />
      The responsible person will receive a weekly reminder by email.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Recitifying Vulnerabilities">
    <description>
      After closing a task of the type <b>Recitify vulnerability</b> all relations between assets and scenarios will
      be deleted whereas the vulnerability itself will remain in verinice but has no more effect!<br />
      <br />
      The status of the linked control will be set to <b>Implemented > Yes</b> when no more assets are linked to the
      scenario. In case there exist additional links between assets and scenarios resulting out of other tasks, the
      control status will be set to <b>Implemented > partially</b>.<br />
      <br />
      In this way it is guaranteed that a vulnerability will only be set to the status <b>Recitified</b>, if all
      responsible persons recitified the vulnerability in their field of responsibility.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Closing Tasks for not Rectified Vulnerabilities">
    <description>
      Tasks for not recitified vulnerabilities will be closed in the workflow after 3 weeks automatically to reduce
      the number of open tasks. This behavior is implemented to reflect the fact, that in real life it is not always
      possible to recitify an enormous number of vulnerabilities immediately. Due to the fact that vulnerability scans
      are performed on a regular base, vulnerabilities that have not been rectified will be detected again and the
      corresponding tasks will be created according. Therefore the whole process aims at optimising security while
      keeping the effort as low as possible.<br />
      <br />
      The Greenbone vulnerability scan can be configured to transfer the found vulnerabilities to <b>verince.PRO</b>
      automatically. In this case <b>verinice.PRO</b> compares the current scan result with the implementation status
      according to the workflow and performs necessary adjustments. Vulnerabilities that have been set to
      <b>recitified</b> falsely will be reopened - <b>verinice.PRO</b> recreates the correct links between assets and
      scenarios. In this process verinice does not create double entries but recognises previously imported assets and
      vulnerabilities and keeps those in the organisation.
    </description>
  </item>

</cheatsheet>
