<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?>
<cheatsheet title="Getting started with information security assessments">

  <intro>
    <description>
      <b>Welcome to verinice information security assessments!</b>
      <br /><br />
      This tutorial will help you to conduct your first information security assessment!
    </description>
  </intro>

  <item title="Switch to the security assessment perspective">
    <description>
      First you have to create a new security assessment. You should be in the security assessment
      perspective. If not, you can open it via <b>View -> Show Perspective... -> Security Assessment
      Perspective</b>.
      <br /><br />
      You will find the security assessment view at the left side of the workbench.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Create a new security assessment">
    <description>
      Click the button <b>New</b> in the security assessment view or choose from <b>File > Add new
      security assessment</b> from the menu.
      <br /><br />
      The new security assessment will appear in the view. Double-click it to bring up the editor view.
      Change the name from "[My Company]" to your company's name.
      <br /><br />
      Save by clicking on <b>File > Save</b> or by pressing <b>Ctrl-S</b> on your keyboard.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Open the first category">
    <description>
      Expand the security assessment by clicking the small arrow to the left of the node's icon.
      Expand "Controls" and then the first category by clicking the small arrow on the left.
      <br /><br />
      You should be able to see a number of categories from "Security Policy" to "Access Control".
      These categories contain questions that will help you to evaluate your current information security
      level for the most important topics.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Answering questions">
    <description>
      Double-click the first question to open the editor. Simultaneously, the Object Browser will
      show the question and a selection of maturity levels.
      <br /><br />
      Read the descriptions to decide which maturity level you have reached in your organization.
      You may have to consult other employees or do some internal research to answer the question
      correctly.
      <br /><br />
      Choose the correct maturity level in the editor below the browser view. You can add a public and
      a private comment. The public comment will be included in a database export. Private comments are
      just for yourself. They never leave your local database.
      <br /><br />
      Save your changes by pressing <b>Ctrl-S</b> or by choosing <b>File -> Save</b>.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Generate a report">
    <description>
      Continue in the same way with the next question. As you go along, you will notice that the chart
      in the bottom left corner of the screen begins to reflect your answers.
      <br /><br />
      When you are done answering all questions, you may want to generate a report for management or another
      party, which you can then send them via email or other means. You can do so by selecting
      <b>File > Generate Report...</b>.
      <br /><br />
      Select "Information Security Assessment Report" and a enter a filename under which the
      report will be saved, then click <b>OK</b>.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Export results">
    <description>
      When you are done answering all questions, you can export your results to send them to another party.
      You can do so by clicking the <b>Export</b>
      button in the security assessment view or by selecting <b>File > Security Assessment > Export to
      file</b>.
      <br /><br />
      You have to choose a filename under which the report will be saved. The exported file is always
      encrypted, so you also have to choose a password or a certificate for encryption. Once you're done,
      press <b>OK</b>.
    </description>
  </item>

  <item title="Finished">
    <description>
      Congratulations on conducting your first security assessment of your information security status.
      If you wish to go further and are thinking about actually establishing an information security
      management system (ISMS) in your company, you can go back to the welcome screen by choosing
      <b>Help > Welcome</b>.
      <br /><br />
      This time, select the option "Establish a management system for information security (ISMS)".
      You will be directed to the ISM Perspective with another tutorial to guide you.
    </description>
    <onCompletion>
      This concludes this tutorial. Don't forget to visit <b>http://www.verinice.com/en</b> for more information
      and news!
    </onCompletion>
  </item>
  
</cheatsheet>
