<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?>
<cheatsheet title="Getting started with information security assessments">
    <intro>
        <description>
            <b>Welcome to verinice information security assessments!</b>
            <br/>
            <br/>
            This tutorial will help you to conduct your first information security assessment!
        </description>
    </intro>

    <item title="Switch to the security assessment perspective">
        <description>
            <br/><br/>
First you have to create a new security assessment. You should be in the security assessment perspective. 
If not, you can go there by choosing from the menu:
            <b>View -> Show Perspective... -> Security Assessment Perspective</b>.
            
            You will find the security assessment view on left side of the Window.
        </description>
    </item>

    <item title="Create a new security assessment">
        <description>
        Click the <b>NEW</b> button in the security assessment view or choose from
        the menu: <b>File -> Add new security assessment</b>
        <br/><br/>
        The new security assessment will appear in the view. Double-click on it
        to bring up the editor view. Change the name from "[My Company]" to your actual company's name.
        <br/><br/>
        Save by clicking on <b>File -> Save</b> or by pressing the keys <b>Ctrl-S</b>.
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item title="Open the first category">
        <description>
        Expand the security assessment 
        by clicking the small arrow to the left of the node's icon. Expand "Controls" and then the first category by clicking the small arrow on the left.
        <br/><br/>
        You should be able to see a
        number of categories from "Security Policy" to "Access Control". These
        categories contain questions that will help you to evaluate your current
        information security level for the most important topics.
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item title="Answering questions">
    <description>
        Double-click on the first question to open the editor.
        Simultaneously, the Object Browser will show you the question and a selection of maturity levels.
        <br/><br/>
        Read the descriptions to decide which maturity level you have reached in your organization. You may have to consult 
        other employees or do some internal research to answer the question correctly. 
        <br/>
        Choose the correct maturity level in the editor below the browser view. You can also add a public comment. This comment
        will be included in a database export. You can also add a private comment just for yourself. The private comment 
        will always stay in your local database.
        <br/><br/>
        Save your changes by pressing <b>Ctrl-S</b> or by choosing <b>File -> Save</b>.
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item title="Generate a report">
      <description>
        Continue in the same way with the next question. As you go along, you will notice
        that the chart in the bottom left corner of the screen begins to reflect your answers.
        <br/><br/>
        When you are done answering all questions, you may want to generate a report for management or another party, which you can then send them by e-mail 
        or other means.
        You can do so by choosing
        <b>File -&gt; Generate Report...</b>.
        <br/><br/>
        Choose the &quot;Information Security Assessment Report&quot; and a enter a filename under which the report will be saved, then click OK.
         </description>
    </item>
    
    <item title="Export results">
      <description>
        When you are done answering all questions, you can export your results to send them to another party.
        You can do so by clicking the <b>Export</b> button in the security assessment view or by choosing from the menu <b>File -&gt; Security Assessment -&gt; Export to file</b>.
        <br/><br/>
        You have to choose a filename under which the report will be saved. The exported file is always encrypted, so you also
        have to choose a password or a certificate for encryption. Once you&apos;re done, press OK. 
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item title="Finished">
      <description>
    Congratulations on conducting your first security assessment of your information security status. If you wish to 
    go further and are thinking about actually establishing an information security management system (ISMS) in your
    company, you can go back to the welcome screen by choosing <b>Help -> Welcome</b>.
    <br/><br/>
    This time, select the option "Establish an ISMS". You will be directed to the ISM Perspective with another tutorial to guide you. 
     </description>
    <onCompletion>
        This concludes this tutorial. Don't forget to go to <b>http://verinice.org</b> for more information and news!
    </onCompletion>
    </item>
</cheatsheet>
